Chad Young

677 Arrowood Court Los Altos, CA 94024 (650) 933-0747 chady64@outlook.com

SUMMARY

I am a game engineer who has always been fascinated with game engines like Game Maker Studio since I was young. I currently have experience with various game engines such as Unreal Engine and Unity, as well as programming languages like C++, Python, and Java. I also have experience working with teams, managing my own time and learning new skills quickly, which are especially important skills in the career field.

KNOWLEDGE AND SKILLS

Main Focus

Unity, Unreal Engine, Godot, Game Design, QA Testing, C++, Unreal Blueprints, C#.

Knowledgeable In

Java, Javascript, Python, Lua, QT

Soft Skills

Attention to detail, creativity, writing, fast work environments, teamwork.

EXPERIENCE

CTY Technologies

March 2024-Present

Founder and President

- Developed business plan, strategy and launched the company.
- Initiated business and marketing operations.
- Created a company website using Wix.
- Starting as an electronic repair business.
- Planned game studio operations for future in Game Developer Club.

Website coming soon.

University of Silicon Valley

2021-Present

Game Developer Club - Vice President

- Helped manage the club with the president and other leaders.
- Spearheaded efforts to re-establish game prototyping within the club.
- Attended events in the club, including a game testing event.
- Working on a new game concept with club members.

The Museum of Art and Digital Entertainment, Oakland, CA

2019-2024

Volunteer Technical Assistant

- Repaired video game consoles, including problem diagnosis and repair of game units.
- Configured consoles and other game units for temporary museum exhibits.
- Worked on program ISOBreaker for helping the team read ISO files.

Back of House Team Member

• Maintain kitchen cleanliness, assist with food preparation, and restock kitchen supplies.

EDUCATION

University of Silicon Valley, San Jose

September 2021-Present

Bachelor of Science, Game Engineering

GPA: 3.8

Foothill College, Los Altos Hills

September 2019 - December 2021

GPA: 3.8

PROJECTS

Muskler

- Director of game project.
- Created Game Design Document as well as documentation.
- Engineer of game project.
- Part of the Game Dev Club at USV.

ISOBreaker

- Uses Visual Studio 2022 and QT 6.5
- QT C++ Program created from scratch with no prior experience.
- Supports multiple ISO formats, including standard, GameCube, and Xbox.
- Easy to use and a good alternative to other programs like ISOBuster.
- Shared with Volunteers at the Museum of Art and Digital Entertainment.

Trees for Speed

Oublivious

- Finished using the Godot game engine.
- Lead the development team and directed various concepts for the game.
- Programmed weapon mechanics, as well as player movement for the game.
- Worked with level designers on creating the level for the game.

Project Bookcraft

- Worked on the "Bookkeeping" as well as the "Bookchanging" modes.
- Participated in the QA Testing sessions of the game.
- Implemented and documented various systems, including the dialogue system and inventory system.
- Profiled and fixed various performance problems with the game.

Return of the Tomb Raider

- Unreal Engine 5.4 Project.
- Worked on the Graveyard level found in the final game.
- Implemented the inventory system used in the game.

Graybox

- Programmed using Unity 3 Engineer as well as level designer for the project. Programmed character movement and power-ups for the game.

PC/Cell Phone Repair Projects and Activities

• PC/Cell Phone Diagnostic/Repair/Refurbishment